David Craig Penner

4925 Dufferin Street
Toronto, Ontario
M3H 5T6

✓ david.craigpenner@mail.utoronto.com

✓ www.davidcraigpenner.com

in davidcraigpenner

Curriculum Vitae

My research is focused on investigating, and potentially improving, the properties of high-order generalized summation-by-parts operators and methods in the context of problems of increasing practical relevance, for example, fluid flow problems governed by the compressible Navier-Stokes equations.

Education

2016/9-present University of Toronto Institute for Aerospace Studies, Toronto, ON.

Ph.D., Aerospace Engineering, Sept 2021 (Expected)

Advisor: Professor David W. Zingg Direct transfer from M.A.Sc. to Ph.D.

2011/9–2016/5 University of Saskatchewan, Saskatoon, SK.

B.Sc., Mechanical Engineering, May 2016

Great Distinction

Experience

Research

2016/9-present Graduate Student Researcher, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON.

 ${\it Project:} \ \ {\it Development} \ \ {\it and} \ \ {\it investigation} \ \ {\it of} \ \ {\it efficient} \ \ {\it high-order} \ \ {\it generalized} \ \ {\it summation-by-parts}$

operators for computational fluid dynamics

Advisor: Professor David W. Zingg

2014/5–2014/8 Undergraduate Student Researcher, University of Saskatchewan, Saskatoon, SK.

Project: Investigate the effect of Chromium on diamond deposition on ferrous substrates using microwave plasma chemical vapor deposition

Advisor: Professor Qiaoqin Yang

Industry

2015/5–2015/8 Student Field Engineer, PCL Construction, Regina, SK.

- Created a set of interactive, electronic construction drawings
- Supervised and directed subcontractors
- Received the highest student performance rating upon completion of work term

2013/5–2013/8 Engineering Technologist, Ground Engineering Consultants Ltd., Regina, SK.

- Conducted concrete sampling and concrete cylinder strength testing
- Performed foundation inspections
- Completed topographic surveys

2016/5–2016/8 Farm Hand, Schiller Organics, Regina, SK.

- Completed construction projects (carpentry and sheet metal)
- Operated and maintained heavy farm machinery
- Completed welding projects

David Craig Penner Curriculum Vitae

Scholarships, honours, and awards

2018/7International Summer School Scholarship, Beijing, China9000 CNY2017/9-2020/1University of Toronto Fellowship34 000 CAD2016/9-2017/6International HPC Summer School Scholarship, Boulder, Colorado935 CAD2016/9-2017/8NSERC Alexander Graham Bell Master's Scholarship17 500 CAD2016/9Mary H. Beatty Fellowships5000 CAD2016/5University of Saskatchewan M.Sc. Scholarship (Declined)17 000 CAD2016/3Most Innovative Mechanical Engineering 4th Year Capstone Design Project75 CAD2016/1Nortek Air Solutions Canada Award2000 CAD2016/1Douglas Durie Memorial Fund1000 CAD2016/1University of Saskatchewan Scholarships3000 CAD
2017/6 International HPC Summer School Scholarship, Boulder, Colorado 935 CAD 2016/9–2017/8 NSERC Alexander Graham Bell Master's Scholarship 17 500 CAD 2016/9 Mary H. Beatty Fellowships 5000 CAD 2016/5 University of Saskatchewan M.Sc. Scholarship (Declined) 17 000 CAD 2016/3 Most Innovative Mechanical Engineering 4 th Year Capstone Design Project 2016/3 3 rd place – Most Innovative 4 th Year Capstone Design Project 75 CAD 2016/1 Nortek Air Solutions Canada Award 2000 CAD 2016/1 Douglas Durie Memorial Fund 1000 CAD
2016/9-2017/8NSERC Alexander Graham Bell Master's Scholarship17 500 CAD2016/9Mary H. Beatty Fellowships5000 CAD2016/5University of Saskatchewan M.Sc. Scholarship (Declined)17 000 CAD2016/3Most Innovative Mechanical Engineering 4th Year Capstone Design Project75 CAD2016/33rd place - Most Innovative 4th Year Capstone Design Project75 CAD2016/1Nortek Air Solutions Canada Award2000 CAD2016/1Douglas Durie Memorial Fund1000 CAD
2016/9 Mary H. Beatty Fellowships 5000 CAD 2016/5 University of Saskatchewan M.Sc. Scholarship (Declined) 17 000 CAD 2016/3 Most Innovative Mechanical Engineering 4 th Year Capstone Design Project 2016/3 3 rd place – Most Innovative 4 th Year Capstone Design Project 75 CAD 2016/1 Nortek Air Solutions Canada Award 2000 CAD 2016/1 Douglas Durie Memorial Fund 1000 CAD
2016/5 University of Saskatchewan M.Sc. Scholarship (Declined) 17 000 CAD 2016/3 Most Innovative Mechanical Engineering 4 th Year Capstone Design Project 2016/3 3 rd place – Most Innovative 4 th Year Capstone Design Project 75 CAD 2016/1 Nortek Air Solutions Canada Award 2000 CAD 2016/1 Douglas Durie Memorial Fund 1000 CAD
2016/3 Most Innovative Mechanical Engineering $4^{\rm th}$ Year Capstone Design Project 2016/3 $3^{\rm rd}$ place – Most Innovative $4^{\rm th}$ Year Capstone Design Project 75 CAD 2016/1 Nortek Air Solutions Canada Award 2000 CAD 2016/1 Douglas Durie Memorial Fund 1000 CAD
2016/33rd place – Most Innovative 4th Year Capstone Design Project75 CAD2016/1Nortek Air Solutions Canada Award2000 CAD2016/1Douglas Durie Memorial Fund1000 CAD
2016/1Nortek Air Solutions Canada Award2000 CAD2016/1Douglas Durie Memorial Fund1000 CAD
2016/1 Douglas Durie Memorial Fund 1000 CAD
· -
2016/1 University of Saskatchewan Scholarships 3000 CAD
2015/1 Douglas Durie Memorial Fund 2000 CAD
2015/1 W. R. (Buck) Staples Scholarship 2300 CAD
2015/1 University of Saskatchewan Scholarships 3000 CAD
2014/5–2014/8 NSERC Undergraduate Student Research Award 5625 CAD
2012/9– $2016/5$ Dean's Honour Roll in Engineering
2012/9–2013/4 David Dube and Heather Ryan Huskies Men's Football Award 4300 CAD
2011/9–2012/4 Huskie Football Foundation Awards 4000 CAD

Journal publications (refereed)

- [2] D. A. Craig Penner and D. W. Zingg, "Superconvergent Functional Estimates from Tensor-Product Generalized Summation-by-Parts Discretizations in Curvilinear Coordinates," *Journal of Scientific Computing*, vol. 82, Feb. 2020. DOI: 10.1007/s10915-020-01147-7.
- [1] X. Sun, H. Ma, L. Yang, M. Sanchez-Pasten, D. Craig Penner, Y. Li, and Q. Yang, "Metal Dusting, Carburization and Diamond Deposition on Fe-Cr Alloys in CH4-H2 Plasma Atmospheres," *Corrosion Science*, vol. 98, pp. 619–625, Sep. 2015. DOI: 10.1016/j.corsci.2015.06.001.

Conference proceedings (refereed)

- [2] D. A. Craig Penner and D. W. Zingg, "Generalized Summation-by-Parts Methods: Coordinate Transformations, Quadrature Accuracy, and Functional Superconvergence," in *AIAA Aviation 2019 Forum*, Dallas, Texas: American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics, Jun. 2019. DOI: https://doi.org/10.2514/6.2019-2952.
- [1] D. A. Craig Penner and D. W. Zingg, "High-Order Artificial Dissipation Operators Possessing the Summation-by-Parts Property," in 2018 Fluid Dynamics Conference, Atlanta, Georgia: American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics, Jun. 2018. DOI: 10.2514/6.2018-4165.

David Craig Penner Curriculum Vitae

Presentations (excluding the above proceedings)

- [3] D. A. Craig Penner, A. L. Marchildon, K. J. Mattalo, S. Shadpey, and D. W. Zingg, "Novel High-Order Summation-by-Parts Methods for Computational Fluid Dynamics," Poster presentation, 1st Computational Science and Engineering Symposium, University of Toronto Institute for Aerospace Studies, Toronto, Ontario, Canada, May 2019.
- [2] D. A. Craig Penner, "High-Order Artificial Dissipation Operators Possessing the Summation-by-Parts Property," Oral presentation, 2018 International Graduate Summer School in Aeronautics and Astronautics, Beihang University, Beijing, China, Jul. 2018.
- [1] D. A. Craig Penner, "Development and Investigation of Efficient High-Order Generalized Summation-by-Parts Operators for Computational Fluid Dynamics," Oral presentation, 2017 International High-Performance Computing Summer School, University of Colorado Boulder, Boulder, Colorado, United States of America, Jun. 2017.

Teaching

- Fall 2017 Graduate Teaching Assistant, Fundamentals of Computational Fluid Dynamics
 - 2018 (AER 1316H), University of Toronto.
 - 2019 Instructor: Professor David W. Zingg Responsibilities: marking, guest lecturer

Mentoring

Assisted in the supervision of the following students

- 2018/5-2018/8 Alireza Razavi, Bachelor of Applied Science, University of Toronto.
 - Project: Applying optimized summation-by-parts operators to cut cell nodal distributions
- 2018/5–2018/8 Edward (Jun Tai) Luo, Bachelor of Applied Science, University of Toronto.

Project: Optimal boundary closures for high-order artificial dissipation operators satisfying the summation-by-parts property

Computer skills

underline denotes extensive use

Languages <u>Fortran</u>, <u>MATLAB</u>, Python, C++ Environments <u>UNIX terminal</u>, <u>Windows</u>
Software SolidWorks, ICEM CFD, Tecplot Microsoft Excel, Word, PowerPoint

Professional memberships

2017/11-present Student Member, American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics (AIAA)

Other activities

2011/9–2013/8 **Athlete**, University of Saskatchewan Huskies Men's Football Team, Saskatoon, SK. Competed with the University of Saskatchewan Football Team for two years.